

OLGA VARENNIKAVA

Communication & Graphic Designer

604-441-7424 olga.varennikava@gmail.com www.olgav.net

ABOUT

I've been working in the industry for the past 3 years and I'm very inspired how creative thinking and fresh ideas grab attention and cause a communication to be noticed and understood.

I'm proud to deliver logo designs, brand identities, promotional print and digital materials, web and UI/UX designs to connect businesses with their audience, communicate brands' messages in a memorable way, and to create strong relationships through experience that reinforces the commercial and emotional value of the company.

SKILLS

- Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign
- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4
- Responsive web design
- UI/UX design
- Photography
- Typography
- Colour theory
- Design rules & principles

ATTRIBUTES

- Creative, self-motivated & self-driven
- · Organized & detail oriented
- Hardworking & responsible
- Eager to learn & improve existing skills
- Have positive & optimistic attitude
- Speak English, French, Russian & Belarussian

WORK EXPERIENCE

GRAPHIC & WEB DESIGNER

Paintshield Technology Corporation March 2015-June 2016

- Designed logo and brand identity, collateral materials, marketing digital and print documents, presentational brochures, and flyers helping to build up the business awareness on the market.
- Oversaw projects designed by the design team assuring the visual identity is consistent and is adherent to the company's branding guidelines.
- Designed and developed the company's website using designated CMS.
- Art directed and designed several social media promotional banners.
- Designed graphics for the web site, blog posts, and promotional documents.
- Created website templates to be customized by company's clients.
- Did photo edits.

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Privatis Technology Corporation March 2014–June 2016

- Working both independently and closely with the marketing team I was responsible for designing marketing promotional materials for web and print, ensuring that the visual identity follows brand standards.
- Designed a marketing pitch presentation and various infographics in order to present a complex data set in a simplified and visually engaging way to directly reach the core audience.
- Designed social media graphics and web banners using marketing best practices.
- Assisted in UI/UX design for the company's Android application.
- Designed the landing page, email campaigns and social media graphics to help to promote the app.

COMMUNICATION DESIGNER

Freelance

June 2013-March 2015

- Designed logos and developed brand identities, helping companies to stand out among competitors.
- Designed brochures, banners, marketing documents, promotional flyers, booklets, eblasts for external clients.
- Consulted with clients to develop graphic pieces in order to meet the communication needs and to connect them with their customers.
- Did UI/UX design for an Android application.
- Designed landing pages.
- Designed responsive website mockups.

EDUCATION

DIPLOMA IN GRAPHIC DESIGN

Visual College of Art and Design

2012-2014

Studied graphic design with a focus on branding and advertising.

BACHELOR DEGREE IN TRANSLATION

Minsk Linguistic University

2003-2008

Studied translation in written and oral form of communication. Major in simultaneous and consecutive interpreting and translation (French and Russian).